<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Tidy Finance Blog</title>
<link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>The RSS feed of the blog on tidy-finance.org</description>
<language>en</language>
<generator>quarto-1.3.433</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Comparing Fama-French Three vs Five Factors</title>
  <dc:creator>Christoph Scheuch</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/fama-french-three-vs-five-factors/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ In our book chapter <a href="../../r/replicating-fama-and-french-factors">Replicating Fama and French Factors</a>, we show how to construct factor portfolios that are fairly close to the popular data from <a href="https://mba.tuck.dartmouth.edu/pages/faculty/ken.french/data_library.html">Prof.&nbsp;Kenneth French finance data library</a>. In this blog post, I want to elaborate a bit more on the subtle differences between the size and value data in the Fama-French three (FF3) and five (FF5) factor data. ]]></description>
  <category>Data</category>
  <category>Replication</category>
  <guid>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/fama-french-three-vs-five-factors/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/fama-french-three-vs-five-factors/thumbnail.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Convert Raw TRACE Data to a Local SQLite Database</title>
  <dc:creator>Kevin Riehl</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lukas Müller</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/convert-raw-trace-data/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ Corporate bond research is gaining momentum, but data availability can be a challenge for most researchers. While FINRA makes its TRACE Enhanced Data on U.S. corporate bond trading available through vendors such as Wharton Research Data Services (WRDS), not every researcher has access to these services. Alternatively, FINRA offers its Enhanced Historical Data and Academic Data (the latter exclusively) as one-off purchases. However, organizing this data can be complex and time consuming due to the nested and zipped structure of raw TXT files, making it cumbersome for researchers to explore the exciting world of fixed income securities. ]]></description>
  <category>Data</category>
  <guid>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/convert-raw-trace-data/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/convert-raw-trace-data/thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tidy Collaborative Filtering: Building A Stock Recommender</title>
  <dc:creator>Christoph Scheuch</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/tidy-collaborative-filtering/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ Recommender systems are a key component of our digital lifes, ranging from e-commerce, online advertisements, movie recommendations, or more generally all kinds of product recommendations. A recommender system aims to efficiently deliver personalized content to users based on a large pool of potentially relevant information. In this blog post, I illustrate the concept of recommender systems by building a simple stock recommendation tool that relies on publicly available portfolios from the social trading platform <a href="https://wikifolio.com/">wikifolio.com</a>. The resulting recommender proposes stocks to investors who already have their own portfolios and look for new investment opportunities. The underlying assumption is that the wikifolio traders hold stock portfolios that can provide meaningful inspiration for other investors. The resulting stock recommendations of course do not constitute any investment advice and rather serve an illustrative purpose. ]]></description>
  <category>Recommender System</category>
  <guid>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/tidy-collaborative-filtering/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/tidy-collaborative-filtering/thumbnail.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="99" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Non-standard errors in portfolio sorts</title>
  <dc:creator>Patrick Weiss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/nse-portfolio-sorts/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ Welcome to our latest blog post where we delve into the intriguing world of non-standard errors<sup>1</sup>, a crucial aspect of academic research, which also is addressed in financial economics. These non-standard errors often stem from the methodological decisions we make, adding an extra dimension of uncertainty to the estimates we report. I had the pleasure of working with Stefan Voigt on a contribution to Menkveld et al.&nbsp;(2023), which was an exciting opportunity to shape the first discussions on non-standard errors. ]]></description>
  <category>Replications</category>
  <guid>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/nse-portfolio-sorts/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/nse-portfolio-sorts/thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Construction of a Historical S&amp;P 500 Total Return Index</title>
  <dc:creator>Christoph Scheuch</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/historical-sp-500-total-return/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ I wanted to simulate simple equity savings plans over long time horizons and many different initiation periods for a story with the German news portal <a href="https://www.t-online.de/finanzen/geld-vorsorge/geldanlage/id_88931406/exklusive-daten-simulation-so-verlieren-sie-langfristig-kein-geld-an-der-boerse.html">t-online</a>. The good thing is that the S&amp;P 500 index provides a great starting point as it is easily available since 1928 via <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/%5EGSPC/">Yahoo Finance</a>. However, I wanted my savings plans to be accumulating, i.e., all cash distributions are reinvested in the savings plan. The S&amp;P index is inadequate for this situation as it is a price index that only tracks its components’ price movements. The <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/%5ESP500TR/">S&amp;P 500 Total Return Index</a> tracks the overall performance of the S&amp;P 500 and would be the solution to my problem, but it is only available since 1988. ]]></description>
  <category>Data</category>
  <guid>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/historical-sp-500-total-return/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/historical-sp-500-total-return/thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>What is Tidy Finance?</title>
  <dc:creator>Christoph Scheuch</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stefan Voigt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Patrick Weiss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/op-ed-tidy-finance/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ Empirical finance can be tedious. Many standard tasks, such as cleaning data or forming factor portfolios, require a lot of effort. The code to produce even seminal results is typically opaque. Why should researchers have to reinvent the wheel over and over again? ]]></description>
  <category>Op-Ed</category>
  <guid>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/op-ed-tidy-finance/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/op-ed-tidy-finance/thumbnail.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="86" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tidy Finance at Workshops for Ukraine</title>
  <dc:creator>Patrick Weiss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/workshops-for-ukraine/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/dariia-mykhailyshyna/main">Dariia Mykhailyshyna</a>, an Economics PhD student at the University of Bologna, set up a collection of workshops that can be accessed in exchange for a donation in support of Ukraine. We contributed two workshops based on our book <a href="../../index.html">Tidy Finance With R</a>. The seminars are recorded and available on demand, and the collection is continuously expanded with interesting topics. Check out the <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/dariia-mykhailyshyna/main/r-workshops-for-ukraine">extensive workshop program</a> to register for upcoming events and get recordings and materials of the previous workshops. ]]></description>
  <category>Workshops</category>
  <guid>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/workshops-for-ukraine/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/workshops-for-ukraine/thumbnail.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="85" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tidy Finance at the useR!2022 Conference</title>
  <dc:creator>Patrick Weiss</dc:creator>
  <link>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/user-conference-2022/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ We had the pleasure of presenting our book at the virtual <a href="https://user2022.r-project.org/">useR!2022</a> conference with 1,227 registered participants from 96 countries. It was great fun! Since it was recorded, you can find the video of my presentation below. ]]></description>
  <category>Conferences</category>
  <guid>https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/user-conference-2022/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://www.tidy-finance.org/blog/user-conference-2022/thumbnail.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="84" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
